STEPHEN LEISY

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER



<u>stleisy@gmail.com</u>



im /stephen-leisy



/stephen-leisy



503-789-4225

TECH STACK

Development

JavaScript HTML

CSS

Testing

Jest

Dev Tools Git/Github Heroku

Postman PGAdmin

Netlify **VSCode** **DataBase**

PostgreSQL

SQL

Libraries & **Frameworks**

React

Express.js Node.js

Redux Superagent

Axios

Other Skills

TDD

pair-programming

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Alchemy Code Lab

2020 | Full Stack JavaScript Engineer

800+ hours of remote full-stack software development with an emphasis on collaboration, TDD, CS concepts, and agile development.

Portland State University

2010 | Masters Program in Publishing and **Technical Editing**

I only completed one year of the program but maintained a 4.0 GPA and landed a technical editing internship at Welch Allyn.

Oregon State University

2004-2009 | B.A.

Major: English

Minor: Creative Writing

SUMMARY

Collaborative, self-starter in software development with a preference for front-end work. I believe web development is creative at its core and enjoy utilizing my technical skill and artistic background to build practical applications with elegant, clean code. Currently seeking a position with a diverse team of developers to grow my skillset and collaborate with. I also played in an indie-rock band for a decade, toured all over the U.S. and love to talk about professional basketball.

SELECTED PROJECTS



A collaborative, physics-based music creation room for inquisitive minds-- featuring a cohesive UI design with abstract art and animations. I worked on an all-remote team of seven developers in a two week sprint to make this project a reality and contributed to numerous portions of its code base, including the incorporation of Matter is and Tone.js within a React framework. Most notably, I implemented the animations throughout the app using keyframe animations in CSS and React hooks to toggle between element classNames triggering the animations to begin.

Pixel Pusher Code

PostgreSQL, Node.js, express, inquirer, blessed, npm, Heroku, jest

Collaborated with an all-remote group in a week long sprint to create a published npm package allowing the user to draw pictures in the terminal. The app utilizes two prominent Node.js libraries--inquirer and blessed--for its navigation and terminal based UI. I contributed by researching and implementing the inquirer package to work with our oAuth and hit PostgreSQL endpoints that print user images inside the terminal.

Better Weather Code **Deployed**

React, Express, PostgreSQL, Node, Css, Heroku

Full-stack application with mobile-focused CSS that allows a user to find the sunniest weather in their surrounding area. I contributed by finding the API that returns surrounding zip codes in an adjustable radius--a key piece of the apps functionality. I pair programmed the site's React front-end and utilized atomic design. I also assisted in the creation of an endpoint that hits two APIs and uses the methods reduce() and some() to ensure that only unique data is returned.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Bartender

2013-2020 | Double Dragon

Contributed to the bars financial success through friendly and knowledgable service resulting in a large and steady flow of regular customers. I also kept cool and effectively multitasked during busy solo shifts which allowed the bar owner to save on labor costs.

Musician

2011- Present

Founding member of the indie-rock band Genders and contributed to early success by organizing tours, booking/promoting shows, co-writing songs, enginerring recording sessions, screen printing merchandise and more.